I never heard of anybody outside of my circle
在我自己的朋友圈以外
who knows who he is.
我沒看過有誰聽說過他的
Perhaps there is more to the story than I know.
所以也許還有一些內幕我也不知道
I got my hands on this CD and
我第一次拿到這張CD的時
and became very fond of it right away.
候就很喜歡
We were just listening to
我們是在加拿大參加
it at some party in Canada.
一個派對時聽到它的
After that I was given a copy of this CD
在那之後我拿到了這張CD的拷貝
and told the story behind it
對方還告訴我它的故事
that made the CD even more interesting.
讓這張專輯顯得更有趣
This story where
它的故事就是
he was not publishing himself,
歌手本身本來沒有要發表這張專輯
but someone had sneaked into his locker
但有人偷偷打開它的置物櫃
and a copy of the CD was ..
然後一張這專輯的拷貝...
stolen.
就被偷了
Daniel C - THE PIRATE OF LOVE
Then Helgi gets mesmerized
Helgi聽這張專輯的如痴如醉
and he brings the CD to Reykjavik ..
他就把CD帶到冰島首都
and is obsessed with these songs.
然後他為這張專輯深深著迷
And he basically .. somehow
然後他開始....
introduces these songs to people
介紹大家聽
and it's just like a rolling snowball.
結果出現滾雪球般的效應
If I remember correctly
我記得很清楚
how I got to know Daniel C,
我怎麼聽到Daniel C的
I first got to hear it from my friend Palli.
是我朋友Palli放的
It was some guy, somewhere a truckdriver,
感覺是在講一個卡車司機 講了一些地名阿什麼的
that had written lots of songs to the same chick.
然後好像這司機寫了很多首歌給了同一個女的
I know he was supposed to be,
我那時候就猜這傢伙應該
or he is, maybe he's still alive,
或是他現在其實還活著
a Romanian immigrant .. in Canada.
就是一個羅馬尼亞的移民，在加拿大
And he was a weird guy,
而且他是個怪咖
reserved, nobody really knew him.
很自閉 沒什麼人認識他
The story goes that he's in love with this girl.
故事講到他愛上了這女的
And was going to send .. her name is Sherry.
然後要給她...喔她叫Sherry
and he's gonna send her this
他要把CD
CD as a love confession.
給她當表白
And in the end
但最後
she wants nothing to do with him
她對於他 居然什麼都不要
which I don't understand.
這我真的搞不懂
But maybe it's too much
但也許把這做成
making a whole album.
一整張專輯有點超過了
Maybe it would have worked better
如果只是做成一首歌
if it had only been one song.
搞不好會更好
The he disappears all of a sudden
像他消失超突然的
without any.. out of the blue.
就是... 一點跡象都沒有，
Just stops coming in.
只是突然就沒有唱到他了
Ant they had heard that he had some
然後其他人聽說
trouble because of some woman, or something.
他因為女人惹上一些麻煩之類的
I don't think she fell for it.
我不覺得那女生有愛上他
I think he has ..
大概只有男的有...
I don't think they ever got together.
我覺得他們應該從頭到尾都沒有在一起
Like I said, these are all just some
像我剛說的 有些事情真的都只
rumours and you never really ..
是謠言 不然你真的..（不會了解真相)
met someone that just knows it for sure.
還是要有確定的人才能解開謎團，
It's always just like, well there was something
不然什麼都是[好像] 像 好像是
that when he lived in Canada,
他住在加拿大的時候
he lived with some religious family.
跟一個很虔誠的家庭同住
They rented him some basement or something,
他們好像是把地下室還什麼租給他吧
and he starts showing their daughter
結果他開始對這家的
some interest,
女兒有點興趣
which was a bit too young for him.
但其實這女兒太年輕了
And just too young for everybody,
如果仔細想想
if we think about it.
其實對誰都太年輕了
But there were some who thought
但有些人覺得
that it might be her
大概他真的
that he was singing it to.
就是在唱給她聽
But I don't know.
我也不確定
I have a hard time imagining that.
我一直覺得難以想像
Well yes there is this,
但就會有一些這種句子
"Dogs are barking, cats are meowing".
小狗汪汪 小貓喵喵
It's a bit .. well yes, it's not out of the
所以這有一點...
question that maybe it was written to a...
嗯如果你說這是寫給一個
very young .. woman.
很年輕的女人， 也不是不可能
Well the thing is that Sherry is
而事實上這個Sherry 其實
a thirteen year old girl.
是一個十三歲的女孩
Thirteen year old black girl.
十三歲的黑人女孩
That he is supposed to have tricked ..
所以當他有點騙那個女生
in some sort of communication with him.
想跟她暗通款曲的時候
And her parents found out
她爸媽發現了
and all hell broke loose.
還有所有他超齡的愛慕，
That's why he had to leave town.
這也是他為什麼必須離開那裏
It was like he had been driven off,
似乎他就帶著
to the United States
一顆破碎的心
with a broken heart.
從加拿大這樣開到了美國
But I never got to know
但我一直都不知道
if he knew that the CD was stolen
他本人到底知不知道
and that it got into some circulation or ..
他的CD不但被偷 還造成一股旋風
or if they really knew that he was
或著他們早就知道
going to send it to this ..
他會想要
this girl that he sings so much about.
把CD送給他唱了這麼多首的這女孩
I found the CD totally by accident.
我會找到這張CD完全是意外
I found it on a forum
我在一個論壇找到的
but I don't remember what forum it was.
但我忘了是什麼論壇
The first one was "Lonely Life"
第一首就是"Lonely Life" (寂寞的生活)
I was really touched by those songs.
我一聽就很受感動，
I really liked them.
我真的很喜歡這些歌